http://www.epilepsy.com/connect/privacy-policies

Skip to main content
epilepsy.com
FIND US
Donate Now!
#DareTo Launch
24/7 HelplinePatient AssistanceJ Kiffin Penry Patient Travel Assistance Fund
Clinical Trial Patient Assistance Fund
National & Community Resources
Community Forums
Seizure and Epilepsy NewsEpilepsy & Behavior JournalSelect Journal Abstracts4th Biennial Epilepsy Pipeline Update Conference Recap
A Standardized Diagnostic Approach and Ongoing Feedback Improves Outcome in Psychogenic Nonepileptic Seizures
An Evaluation of the Impact of Memory and Mood on Antiepileptic Drug Adherence
Changes in Attitudes of US Adults toward People with Epilepsy
Changing the Approach to Treatment Choice in Epilepsy Using Big Data
Clinical and Economic Burden of Breakthrough Seizures
Cognitive Impairment in Older Adults with Epilepsy: Characterization and Risk Factor Analysis
Determinants of Felt Stigma in Epilepsy
Differential Impact of Contraceptive Methods on Seizures Varies by Antiepileptic Drug Category
Establishing an Adult Epilepsy Diet Center: Experience, Efficacy, and Challenges
Health Care Costs and Use Related to Long or Short Acting Seizure Medications (AEDs) when Used Alone
In Focus: The Everyday Lives of Families of Adult Individuals with Epilepsy
Long-term Seizure and Psychosocial Outcomes of Vagus Nerve Stimulation for Intractable Epilepsy
Perspectives on Seizure Clusters: Gaps in Lexicon, Awareness, and Treatment
Predicting Drug Resistance in Adult Patients with Generalized Epilepsy: A Case Control Study
Self-control of Epileptic Seizures by Nonpharmacological Strategies
Severity of Self-reported Insomnia in Adults with Epilepsy is Related to Comorbid Medical Disorders and Depressive Symptoms
Should we stop saying “epileptic”? A Comparison of the Effect of the Terms “Epileptic” and “Person with Epilepsy”
Symptoms of Anxiety and Depression in School-aged Children with Active Epilepsy
Temporal Lobe Epilepsy is a Predisposing Factor for Sleep Apnea: A Questionnaire Study in Video-EEG Monitoring Unit
Use of Antiepileptic Drugs During Pregnancy and Lactation: Type of information provided by searching Google
A Randomized Controlled Trial of a Manual-based Psychosocial Group Intervention for Young People with Epilepsy (PIE)
Addition of a Hospital Bedside Sitter During Intracranial Stereotactic EEG Monitoring Improves Safety and Seizure Responses in Adult Epilepsy Monitoring Unit
Addressing Barriers to Surgical Evaluation for Patients with Epilepsy
Association between antiepileptic drug dose and long-term response in patients with refractory epilepsy
Association of Sleep with Sudden Unexpected Death in Epilepsy
Becoming Comfortable with "My" Epilepsy: Strategies that Patients Use in the Journey from Diagnosis to Acceptance and Disclosure
Bursts of High-frequency Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (rTMS), Together with Lorazepam, Suppress Seizures in a Rat Kainate Status Epilepticus Model
Children with Autism Spectrum Disorder and Drug-resistant Epilepsy can Benefit from Epilepsy Surgery
Community-based Rehabilitation Offers Cost-effective Epilepsy Treatment in Rural Guinea-Bissau
Counseling by Epileptologists Affects Contraceptive Choices of Women with Epilepsy
Development and Use of the Art Therapy Seizure Assessment Sculpture on an Inpatient Epilepsy Monitoring Unit
Diagnostic Accuracy of Audio-based Seizure Detection in Patients with Severe Epilepsy and an Intellectual Disability
Diazepam Buccal Film for the Treatment of Acute Seizures
Epidemiology of Neurocysticercosis and Epilepsy, is Everything Described?
Epilepsy Surgery in the Underserved Hispanic Population Improves Depression, Anxiety and Quality of Life
Epilepsy by the Numbers: Epilepsy Deaths by Age, Race/Ethnicity, and Gender in the United States Significantly Increased from 2005 to 2014
Experiences and Needs of Parents of Young Children with Active Epilepsy: A Population-Based Study
Folic Acid Use by Women with Epilepsy: Findings of the Epilepsy Birth Control Registry
Health Survey Data on Serious Psychological Distress Among Adults with Epilepsy in All Racial/Ethnic Groups
How do you exercise with epilepsy? Insights into the Barriers and Adaptations to Successfully Exercise with Epilepsy
How often is antiseizure drug-free ketogenic diet therapy achieved?
Ictal Bradyarrhythmias and Asystole Requiring Pacemaker Implantation
Immediate outcomes in early life epilepsy: A contemporary account
Improved Quality of Life and Cognition After Early Vagal Nerve Stimulator Implantation in Children
MINDSET: Clinical Feasibility of Utilizing the Revised Epilepsy Self-management Tool for Spanish Speaking Patients
Mortality in Dravet syndrome:
A review
Most Antidepressant Drugs Are Safe for Patients with Epilepsy at Therapeutic Doses: A Review of the Evidence
Neurobehavioral Problems in Children with Early-onset Epilepsy: A Population-based Study
Parental Stress, Pediatric Quality of Life, and Behavior at Baseline and One-year Follow-up: Results from the FEBSTAT Study
Presurgical Depression and Anxiety Are Not Associated with Worse Epilepsy Surgery Outcome Five Years Postoperatively
Proceedings of the Epilepsy Foundation's 2017 Cannabinoids in Epilepsy Therapy Workshop
Psychiatric and Behavioral Side Effects of Antiepileptic Drugs in Adults with Epilepsy
Recurrent Catamenial Status Epilepticus: Is it Rare or an Under Recognized Phenomenon in Women with Epilepsy?
Seizure-related Variables are Predictive of Attention and Memory in Children with Epilepsy
Social Media in Epilepsy: A Quantitative and Qualitative Analysis
The Co-Occurrence of Epilepsy and Autism: A Systematic Review
The Efficacy of an Educational Program for Parents of Children with Epilepsy (FAMOSES)
The Role of Executive Functioning in Quality of Life in Pediatric Intractable Epilepsy
Understanding the Self-management Skills of Persons with Epilepsy
Usage of EpiFinder Clinical Decision Support in the Assessment of Epilepsy
Utility of Long-term Video-EEG Monitoring for Children with Staring
Visual Field Defects Following Different Resective Procedures for Mesiotemporal Lobe Epilepsy
Vulnerabilities to Antiepileptic Drug (AED) Side Effects in Youth with Epilepsy
Epilepsy Foundation EditorialsEpilepsy Foundation Efforts to Reduce the Impact of Epilepsy-Related Comorbidities: We Can’t Wait
The Epilepsy Pipeline Conference: Accelerating Hope
The New Partnership Between Epilepsy & Behavior and the Epilepsy Foundation
Advancing Public Policy for Epilepsy: The Epilepsy Foundation’s Public Police Institute and Teens Speak Up! Programs
The Epilepsy Foundation Leads in the Rare Epilepsy Network PCORI Award
Epilepsy Matters!
Epilepsy Foundation “#DareTo” Campaign
Epilepsy Foundation Public Awareness Campaigns – 2001 through 2013
National Walk for Epilepsy
Epilepsy Matters: Response to the CDC Report on Death in Children with Epilepsy
Saluting our Leaders
The Epilepsy Foundation is the Voice of People with Epilepsy and Their Families
Stronger Together: The Epilepsy Therapy Project and Epilepsy Foundation decide to merge - Our personal stories and reflections
People with Epilepsy as Partners in Research
Keto NewsGLUT1 Deficiency Syndrome and the Ketogenic Diet
What to Do When Your Child Grows Up and Still Needs the Diet?
Continuing to Combat the Fear of High Cholesterol
Fasting and Absence Epilepsy: Reassessing Both in 2013
3rd International Ketogenic Diet Symposium Recap
The Road to the Ketogenic Diet
Welcome to Chicago! The 3rd International Ketogenic Diet Conference
High Fat and Curry? A Trip to Witness the Indianization of the Ketogenic Diet
Top 10 Ketogenic Diet-Related Articles from 2011
Dietary Treatments and Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome
What to Do When it’s Time to Stop?
Summer Reading on the Ketogenic Diet 2011
EEGs and the Ketogenic Diet
Diets and Adults: an Update for 2011
Top 10 Dietary Treatment Articles of 2010
Will My Child Get a Heart Attack?!?
No! Long-term Use of the Diet is Safe!
New York Times Magazine Cover Story on Ketogenic Diet Therapy for Epilepsy
Excitement in Edinburgh: Report from the 2nd International Dietary Therapies Meeting
October in Edinburgh! Ketogenic Diets 2nd Biannual Conference
Infantile Spasms and the Diet: The Evidence Grows
The Ketogenic Diet Up North
American Epilepsy Society Annual Meeting Recap
Top 10 Articles of 2009
911: Using Ketogenic Diets for Emergencies
Can You "Fine-Tune" the Ketogenic Diet?
Side Effects on the Diet: Prevention, Not Just Treatment
The Ketogenic Diet in a Bottle?
Diet Therapy for Epilepsy in the Mideast
Why is this Night Different from All Other Nights? Mixing Ketogenic Diets and Passover
Is There a Right Way to Do the Diet?
The Consensus Statement is Published!
Does Ketosis Matter?
Discussion at the 2008 American Epilepsy Society
Top 10 Ketogenic Diet Articles for 2008
A Remembrance of Life on the Ketogenic Diet 60 Years Later!
Using the Diet for Epilepsy First?
Siblings and the Ketogenic Diet
Grace’s Magic Diet: A Child’s Story
Ketogenic Diets: Not Just for Epilepsy any Longer
Ketogenic Diet Centers in the United States
Newly-released Results from a Randomized and Controlled Study of the Ketogenic Diet in London
The First International Dietary Treatments for Epilepsy and other Neurologic Disorders Meeting Report
The Ketogenic Diet and Antiepileptic Drugs: A Good Mix?
Ketogenic Recipes for Easter and Passover
Let’s Meet! Exciting Past (and Future) Ketogenic Diet Conferences
Hearts, Flowers, and Almond Bread
Top 10 Ketogenic Diet Articles in the Medical Literature of 2007
Winter Holidays
Side Effects on the Ketogenic Diet: Identification and Treatment
A Happy Ketogenic Thanksgiving
Laboratory Notes on the Ketogenic Diet
Try It: They Might Like It!
The MCT Diet
A Mother's Plan for the Ketogenic Diet
Preparing Yourself, Your Family, and Your Child for the Ketogenic Diet
The Low Glycemic Index Treatment and the Ketogenic Diet
Modified Atkins Diet – More on the Plate than Ever
Do Ketogenic Diets Work for Adults with Epilepsy? Yes!
Ketogenic Diet Research
Basic Science of Epilepsy
PubMed Articles Feeds
Local Office Spotlight Archive
Contact Us
Find an Epilepsy SpecialistFind an Epilepsy Center
Find a Doctor
Find a Clinical Trial
#DareTo Launch
24/7 HelplinePatient AssistanceJ Kiffin Penry Patient Travel Assistance Fund
Clinical Trial Patient Assistance Fund
National & Community Resources
Community Forums
Seizure and Epilepsy NewsEpilepsy & Behavior JournalSelect Journal Abstracts4th Biennial Epilepsy Pipeline Update Conference Recap
A Standardized Diagnostic Approach and Ongoing Feedback Improves Outcome in Psychogenic Nonepileptic Seizures
An Evaluation of the Impact of Memory and Mood on Antiepileptic Drug Adherence
Changes in Attitudes of US Adults toward People with Epilepsy
Changing the Approach to Treatment Choice in Epilepsy Using Big Data
Clinical and Economic Burden of Breakthrough Seizures
Cognitive Impairment in Older Adults with Epilepsy: Characterization and Risk Factor Analysis
Determinants of Felt Stigma in Epilepsy
Differential Impact of Contraceptive Methods on Seizures Varies by Antiepileptic Drug Category
Establishing an Adult Epilepsy Diet Center: Experience, Efficacy, and Challenges
Health Care Costs and Use Related to Long or Short Acting Seizure Medications (AEDs) when Used Alone
In Focus: The Everyday Lives of Families of Adult Individuals with Epilepsy
Long-term Seizure and Psychosocial Outcomes of Vagus Nerve Stimulation for Intractable Epilepsy
Perspectives on Seizure Clusters: Gaps in Lexicon, Awareness, and Treatment
Predicting Drug Resistance in Adult Patients with Generalized Epilepsy: A Case Control Study
Self-control of Epileptic Seizures by Nonpharmacological Strategies
Severity of Self-reported Insomnia in Adults with Epilepsy is Related to Comorbid Medical Disorders and Depressive Symptoms
Should we stop saying “epileptic”? A Comparison of the Effect of the Terms “Epileptic” and “Person with Epilepsy”
Symptoms of Anxiety and Depression in School-aged Children with Active Epilepsy
Temporal Lobe Epilepsy is a Predisposing Factor for Sleep Apnea: A Questionnaire Study in Video-EEG Monitoring Unit
Use of Antiepileptic Drugs During Pregnancy and Lactation: Type of information provided by searching Google
A Randomized Controlled Trial of a Manual-based Psychosocial Group Intervention for Young People with Epilepsy (PIE)
Addition of a Hospital Bedside Sitter During Intracranial Stereotactic EEG Monitoring Improves Safety and Seizure Responses in Adult Epilepsy Monitoring Unit
Addressing Barriers to Surgical Evaluation for Patients with Epilepsy
Association between antiepileptic drug dose and long-term response in patients with refractory epilepsy
Association of Sleep with Sudden Unexpected Death in Epilepsy
Becoming Comfortable with "My" Epilepsy: Strategies that Patients Use in the Journey from Diagnosis to Acceptance and Disclosure
Bursts of High-frequency Repetitive Transcranial Magnetic Stimulation (rTMS), Together with Lorazepam, Suppress Seizures in a Rat Kainate Status Epilepticus Model
Children with Autism Spectrum Disorder and Drug-resistant Epilepsy can Benefit from Epilepsy Surgery
Community-based Rehabilitation Offers Cost-effective Epilepsy Treatment in Rural Guinea-Bissau
Counseling by Epileptologists Affects Contraceptive Choices of Women with Epilepsy
Development and Use of the Art Therapy Seizure Assessment Sculpture on an Inpatient Epilepsy Monitoring Unit
Diagnostic Accuracy of Audio-based Seizure Detection in Patients with Severe Epilepsy and an Intellectual Disability
Diazepam Buccal Film for the Treatment of Acute Seizures
Epidemiology of Neurocysticercosis and Epilepsy, is Everything Described?
Epilepsy Surgery in the Underserved Hispanic Population Improves Depression, Anxiety and Quality of Life
Epilepsy by the Numbers: Epilepsy Deaths by Age, Race/Ethnicity, and Gender in the United States Significantly Increased from 2005 to 2014
Experiences and Needs of Parents of Young Children with Active Epilepsy: A Population-Based Study
Folic Acid Use by Women with Epilepsy: Findings of the Epilepsy Birth Control Registry
Health Survey Data on Serious Psychological Distress Among Adults with Epilepsy in All Racial/Ethnic Groups
How do you exercise with epilepsy? Insights into the Barriers and Adaptations to Successfully Exercise with Epilepsy
How often is antiseizure drug-free ketogenic diet therapy achieved?
Ictal Bradyarrhythmias and Asystole Requiring Pacemaker Implantation
Immediate outcomes in early life epilepsy: A contemporary account
Improved Quality of Life and Cognition After Early Vagal Nerve Stimulator Implantation in Children
MINDSET: Clinical Feasibility of Utilizing the Revised Epilepsy Self-management Tool for Spanish Speaking Patients
Mortality in Dravet syndrome:
A review
Most Antidepressant Drugs Are Safe for Patients with Epilepsy at Therapeutic Doses: A Review of the Evidence
Neurobehavioral Problems in Children with Early-onset Epilepsy: A Population-based Study
Parental Stress, Pediatric Quality of Life, and Behavior at Baseline and One-year Follow-up: Results from the FEBSTAT Study
Presurgical Depression and Anxiety Are Not Associated with Worse Epilepsy Surgery Outcome Five Years Postoperatively
Proceedings of the Epilepsy Foundation's 2017 Cannabinoids in Epilepsy Therapy Workshop
Psychiatric and Behavioral Side Effects of Antiepileptic Drugs in Adults with Epilepsy
Recurrent Catamenial Status Epilepticus: Is it Rare or an Under Recognized Phenomenon in Women with Epilepsy?
Seizure-related Variables are Predictive of Attention and Memory in Children with Epilepsy
Social Media in Epilepsy: A Quantitative and Qualitative Analysis
The Co-Occurrence of Epilepsy and Autism: A Systematic Review
The Efficacy of an Educational Program for Parents of Children with Epilepsy (FAMOSES)
The Role of Executive Functioning in Quality of Life in Pediatric Intractable Epilepsy
Understanding the Self-management Skills of Persons with Epilepsy
Usage of EpiFinder Clinical Decision Support in the Assessment of Epilepsy
Utility of Long-term Video-EEG Monitoring for Children with Staring
Visual Field Defects Following Different Resective Procedures for Mesiotemporal Lobe Epilepsy
Vulnerabilities to Antiepileptic Drug (AED) Side Effects in Youth with Epilepsy
Epilepsy Foundation EditorialsEpilepsy Foundation Efforts to Reduce the Impact of Epilepsy-Related Comorbidities: We Can’t Wait
The Epilepsy Pipeline Conference: Accelerating Hope
The New Partnership Between Epilepsy & Behavior and the Epilepsy Foundation
Advancing Public Policy for Epilepsy: The Epilepsy Foundation’s Public Police Institute and Teens Speak Up! Programs
The Epilepsy Foundation Leads in the Rare Epilepsy Network PCORI Award
Epilepsy Matters!
Epilepsy Foundation “#DareTo” Campaign
Epilepsy Foundation Public Awareness Campaigns – 2001 through 2013
National Walk for Epilepsy
Epilepsy Matters: Response to the CDC Report on Death in Children with Epilepsy
Saluting our Leaders
The Epilepsy Foundation is the Voice of People with Epilepsy and Their Families
Stronger Together: The Epilepsy Therapy Project and Epilepsy Foundation decide to merge - Our personal stories and reflections
People with Epilepsy as Partners in Research
Keto NewsGLUT1 Deficiency Syndrome and the Ketogenic Diet
What to Do When Your Child Grows Up and Still Needs the Diet?
Continuing to Combat the Fear of High Cholesterol
Fasting and Absence Epilepsy: Reassessing Both in 2013
3rd International Ketogenic Diet Symposium Recap
The Road to the Ketogenic Diet
Welcome to Chicago! The 3rd International Ketogenic Diet Conference
High Fat and Curry? A Trip to Witness the Indianization of the Ketogenic Diet
Top 10 Ketogenic Diet-Related Articles from 2011
Dietary Treatments and Lennox-Gastaut Syndrome
What to Do When it’s Time to Stop?
Summer Reading on the Ketogenic Diet 2011
EEGs and the Ketogenic Diet
Diets and Adults: an Update for 2011
Top 10 Dietary Treatment Articles of 2010
Will My Child Get a Heart Attack?!?
No! Long-term Use of the Diet is Safe!
New York Times Magazine Cover Story on Ketogenic Diet Therapy for Epilepsy
Excitement in Edinburgh: Report from the 2nd International Dietary Therapies Meeting
October in Edinburgh! Ketogenic Diets 2nd Biannual Conference
Infantile Spasms and the Diet: The Evidence Grows
The Ketogenic Diet Up North
American Epilepsy Society Annual Meeting Recap
Top 10 Articles of 2009
911: Using Ketogenic Diets for Emergencies
Can You "Fine-Tune" the Ketogenic Diet?
Side Effects on the Diet: Prevention, Not Just Treatment
The Ketogenic Diet in a Bottle?
Diet Therapy for Epilepsy in the Mideast
Why is this Night Different from All Other Nights? Mixing Ketogenic Diets and Passover
Is There a Right Way to Do the Diet?
The Consensus Statement is Published!
Does Ketosis Matter?
Discussion at the 2008 American Epilepsy Society
Top 10 Ketogenic Diet Articles for 2008
A Remembrance of Life on the Ketogenic Diet 60 Years Later!
Using the Diet for Epilepsy First?
Siblings and the Ketogenic Diet
Grace’s Magic Diet: A Child’s Story
Ketogenic Diets: Not Just for Epilepsy any Longer
Ketogenic Diet Centers in the United States
Newly-released Results from a Randomized and Controlled Study of the Ketogenic Diet in London
The First International Dietary Treatments for Epilepsy and other Neurologic Disorders Meeting Report
The Ketogenic Diet and Antiepileptic Drugs: A Good Mix?
Ketogenic Recipes for Easter and Passover
Let’s Meet! Exciting Past (and Future) Ketogenic Diet Conferences
Hearts, Flowers, and Almond Bread
Top 10 Ketogenic Diet Articles in the Medical Literature of 2007
Winter Holidays
Side Effects on the Ketogenic Diet: Identification and Treatment
A Happy Ketogenic Thanksgiving
Laboratory Notes on the Ketogenic Diet
Try It: They Might Like It!
The MCT Diet
A Mother's Plan for the Ketogenic Diet
Preparing Yourself, Your Family, and Your Child for the Ketogenic Diet
The Low Glycemic Index Treatment and the Ketogenic Diet
Modified Atkins Diet – More on the Plate than Ever
Do Ketogenic Diets Work for Adults with Epilepsy? Yes!
Ketogenic Diet Research
Basic Science of Epilepsy
PubMed Articles Feeds
Local Office Spotlight Archive
Contact Us
Find an Epilepsy SpecialistFind an Epilepsy Center
Find a Doctor
Find a Clinical Trial
Epilepsy Foundation Terms of Use
Privacy Policy
get the news!
Join our mailing list to stay to date about programs, events, and news about epilepsy.
Email Address
Weekly Newsletters
Epilepsy.com - General Audience
Last updated: March 2020
Welcome to the Epilepsy Foundation.
The Epilepsy Foundation wants to protect the privacy of visitors to our website. The information users voluntarily share with us will be used to improve the quality of our services and to promote public understanding and education about the impact of epilepsy on people's lives. The Foundation has adopted the following privacy policy governing its website. This Privacy Policy applies to Personal Information collected or processed through this website and any other Epilepsy Foundation-operated website, Learning Management System, app, or social media page that links to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "Website"). The Privacy Policy is continuously being revised, and we welcome your thoughts, which you may send to ContactUs@efa.org. Users who have provided us contact information will be informed upon changes to our Privacy Policy.
"Personal Information" is information that identifies or relates to a particular individual. Examples of Personal Information include, among others:
Name
Email address
Phone number
Mailing address
Online identifiers
We use Personal Information for the following purposes:
Providing our Site to you
Analyzing, administering, and improving the Site and our services to users
Enabling secure use of the Site
Sending information and promotional materials
Protecting our rights or our property
Meeting legal obligations
For other purposes related to the reasons for which you provide Personal Information, including when you consent to research and to adding to the general knowledge about epilepsy education and treatment services
What personally identifiable information does the Foundation collect from me?
The Epilepsy Foundation respects the personal privacy of the visitors to our website. We believe keeping your information private and in a secure environment is very important. When you browse the informational portion of our website, you do so anonymously. Personal information is not collected, unless you voluntarily provide us with that information as described below. To participate in our Community, you must provide an email address or user name, and a password. (Please note that it is not a closed community and posts can be found via search engine outside of the website.) We will not share with third parties your name, street address, telephone number or email address without your consent. We do not sell or rent your personal information. We provide no mechanism for an advertiser to reach you, unless you sign up directly with an advertiser or outside vendor.
In order for the Epilepsy Foundation's website, epilepsy.com, apps and other digital platforms to improve its performance and design and to provide you with better services, we track anonymous aggregate usage information through analysis of log files. The type of information collected is basic statistical data, such as channels and sections viewed, time of access and amount of time, search phrases used to reach the Foundation's website, browser type, and anonymized data from users. This information is not personally identifying you in any way, and we cannot get back to you, the user, through this data. We use this aggregated and anonymized information in order to learn what are the most popular sections of our website, for general promotional purposes, and for making decisions about the future strategy and direction of the website. The aggregated and/or anonymized information may also be shared with third parties to promote Epilepsy Foundation services and the website or to add to general knowledge concerning the public's need for epilepsy education and treatment services.
What happens when I sign up with the Foundation online?
You voluntarily provide us with personal information when you choose to become a website member, make a donation, join our Speak Up Speak Out grassroots network or Newsroom, join our Community, subscribe to one of our e-newsletters, use My Seizure Diary, participate in a research campaign, and when you purchase a product from our catalog or online store. The information we collect through these transactions includes such things as your name, address, phone number, email address, seizure information, and, when you make a financial transaction, your credit card number. This allows the Foundation to send you messages and to share information with you that we think you may find useful. We study our users' demographics, interests, records, and behavior based on this information voluntarily provided for a variety of reasons, including to have better information on the needs of people with epilepsy, to do internal research, and to understand how to improve our services.
User records are kept in the strictest of confidence. At times, we select and offer portions of our mailing list to carefully screened organizations that we believe may interest you. We may also ask you to consent to participate in external research related to your records. If you do not want to receive this information, or if you would like to have your name removed from future communications, please let us know by sending an email to ContactUs@efa.org.
What is a cookie and how does the Foundation use them?
When you voluntarily join www.epilepsy.com, make a donation, or purchase an item from the Foundation, a cookie is placed on your computer hard drive. A cookie is a small amount of data stored as a text file. The data contains a unique identification number assigned by our system that recognizes your browser when you come to our computer but does not recognize you as an individual. These cookies remain on your system and are automatically retrieved when you return to our website at a later time. We use cookies to remind us of who you are in order to send you information you have requested and deliver to you a more personalized service. The cookie also allows us to automatically log you in to certain sections of our website without having you re¬enter user name information for each return visit.
You may choose to set the Internet properties of your computer so that you are alerted each time a cookie is being stored on your computer or you may choose to prohibit the collection of cookies all together. In addition, you may delete cookies that have already been stored on your hard drive. If you do prohibit the collection of cookies, understand that you will need to re-enter your email and other information each time you go to the portion of our website that requires the input of identifying information.
How do I change my personal information or stop receiving online information from the Foundation?
If you need to change your personal information, you may do so at any time by simply going to the part of the website where you registered for www.epilepsy.com or purchased items by entering the corrected information.
If you would like to change information in your My Seizure Diary, go to account settings in your diary account. If you wish to unsubscribe from the diary mailing list, contact Diary@efa.org.
If you no longer want to receive newsletters, subscriptions to community forums, marketing or other information from the Foundation sent to your email address, you may unsubscribe by updating your profile on www.epilepsy.com.
If you are a member of the Foundation and would like to update your records, please contact the Foundation by telephone (1-800-332-1000) or letter.
Epilepsy Foundation
ATTN: Epilepsy.com
8301 Professional Place-West
Suite 230
Landover, MD 20785-2353
How does the Foundation protect my confidential information?
If you have shared with us your credit card number in order to purchase an item from our online store or to make a donation to the Foundation, your credit card number is stored on a secure server and is protected by firewalls. The Foundation uses computer encrypted technology to protect your information and this information is kept confidential. The Foundation sometimes contracts with outside vendors and business partners to fulfill customer services and hosting services on the website. When we do so, we enter into confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements with all vendors stating that they will hold information received through our website confidential and will not sell or share user information to any third party or use the information for their own personal use. All employees of the Epilepsy Foundation are held accountable for our privacy principles and each employee is personally responsible for maintaining customer confidence in the company.
Despite these efforts to store Personal Information in a secure operating environment, we cannot guarantee the security of Personal Information during its transmission or its storage on our systems. Further, while we attempt to ensure the integrity and security of Personal Information, we cannot guarantee that our security measures will prevent third parties such as hackers from illegally obtaining access to Personal Information. We do not represent or warrant that Personal Information about you will be protected against, loss, misuse, or alteration by third parties.
You can find more information on the privacy policy related to purchasing from our online store on our online store's website.
You can find more information on the privacy policy related to our Communities on epilepsy.com.
The Foundation may disclose information to law enforcement and other governmental or court authorities in the rare case when we are required to do so or if there is reason to believe that disclosure is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) the Epilepsy Foundation's rights or property, other website users or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities.
How are children who use the Foundation's website protected?
The Foundation is concerned about the safety of minors who use the Internet. We want you and your family to feel secure when visiting our website. Children under 13: Do not send us any information about yourself or your family if you are under age 13 — including information like your name, address or email address — unless you have asked your parents for permission to do so. The Foundation will not knowingly request personal identifying information from children under the age of 18 without parental consent. If we learn that we have personal information from a child under 18, we will delete that information from our database as soon as possible. The Community Forums and Chat Rooms are intended for use by people age 13 or older.
Linked Internet Websites
The Foundation hyperlinks to numerous websites that we believe are of interest to people with epilepsy. We do not control the privacy policies of business partners, advertisers, sponsors, or other websites to which we may provide hyperlinks, and the privacy policies of any of these third parties may differ from ours. When you hyperlink to the website of one of our business partners, advertisers, sponsors, or other websites, you are subject to their privacy policies and not those of the Foundation. The Epilepsy Foundation is not responsible for such provisions and expressly disclaims any and all liability related to the privacy policy or practices of such other websites.
Where should I go if I have a question or a complaint about the Foundation's privacy policy and practices?
The Epilepsy Foundation is committed to efficiency and transparency. We communicate with our supporters, donors, and prospective donors by email, postal mail, phone, and other means, both to request contributions to our cause and to educate the public about epilepsy and seizures, volunteer opportunities, and events in local communities and around the world. These efforts help advance our mission to lead the fight to overcome the challenges of living with epilepsy and to accelerate therapies to stop seizures, find cures, and save lives. As a result, in accordance with the Financial Accounting Standards Board (FASB) guidelines and Internal Revenue Service (IRS) guidance, the Epilepsy Foundation allocates a portion of our fundraising costs to program services. As a nonprofit organization that is exempt from federal taxation, we ensure our donors' money is spent as efficiently and effectively as possible.
My Seizure Diary
By using the Epilepsy Foundation My Seizure Diary feature, you agree to the following terms and conditions:
If you create a personal Diary, you are the only website user who can view and edit your information unless you choose to share your information with other users. If you chose to share your information with others including caregivers, family, or your clinicians, you can view a list of who has access to your information.
Your provision of access to your personal Diary by others may result in third parties misusing your information and is at your own risk.
At any time, you can take away someone's ability to access your personal Diary and that person will no longer be able to read your health-related information, but they may have already seen or may retain a copy of the information.
The Epilepsy Foundation (owner of Epilepsy.com) may use and disclose the health-related information collected from your personal Diary, as described in the Privacy Policy.
You are responsible for taking all reasonable steps to ensure that no unauthorized person shall have access to your Epilepsy Foundation passwords or accounts and for choosing a username and password on Epilepsy.com that would not compromise security on any other website.
For technical help with your personal Diary, you may have to provide your username and password to the website. You should not enter information into the Diary that would identify you personally.
You will not receive any payment or other reimbursement for use of the information entered into the Diary.
The Diary does not provide diagnosis, treatment, or other medical advice. You should seek those from your doctors. If you are having a medical emergency, DO NOT use the Diary to communicate with your doctor or other health care provider.
If you have any additional questions about your privacy on the Epilepsy Foundation's My Seizure Diary, please feel free to contact the Foundation at Diary@efa.org.
If you have any additional questions about your privacy on the Epilepsy Foundation's website, or if you believe that your privacy may have been violated by the Foundation, please feel free to contact the Foundation at ContactUs@efa.org.
Copyright © 1996–2020 Epilepsy Foundation of America, Inc. Landover, MD. All rights reserved.
The information available on epilepsy.com is the property of the Epilepsy Foundation and is protected by copyright and other intellectual property laws. All registered trademarks of the Epilepsy Foundation, including the name "Epilepsy Foundation," "Epilepsy Therapy Project," and the respective logos, cannot be used by anyone for any purpose without the express, written consent of the Epilepsy Foundation.
on: Wednesday, March 25, 2020
Our Mission
The mission of the Epilepsy Foundation is to lead the fight to overcome the challenges of living with epilepsy and to accelerate therapies to stop seizures, find cures, and save lives.
follow us
Search form
Search
24/7 helpline
